<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CHR 2024 on Computational Humanities Research 2024</title>
    <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in CHR 2024 on Computational Humanities Research 2024</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://2024.computational-humanities-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Announcements</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/</guid>
      <description>Proceedings are online The CHR2024 proceedings are now online, comprising 78 papers that reflect the diverse and innovative research happening in Computational Humanities. With the conference just two weeks away, this is a great chance to explore the topics - or just enjoy the work during the conference ... Read More CHR2024 Programme The programme for the CHR 2024 Conference is now available! Over three days, this international and interdisciplinary conference will explore cutting-edge computational approaches to the humanities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Code of conduct</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/code-of-conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/code-of-conduct/</guid>
      <description>Purpose of the Code of Conduct The organisers of the Computational Humanities Research conference are committed to providing a safe and inclusive space, with respectful and equitable treatment for everyone. This code is meant to guide speakers, session chairs, organisers, attendees, and people who might be involved with the conference in other ways. It was inspired by the code of conduct of the BRIDGES 2022 conference published in bridges2022.com/code-of-conduct.&#xA;Approach and principles This code draws on an intersectional perspective, considering the interlocking character of various dimensions such as gender, sexuality, race/ethnicity, class, age, disability, and religion/creed as axes of discrimination.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Discover ARoS Art Museum with Free Voucher</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/aros/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/aros/</guid>
      <description>As a participant in the upcoming CHR2024 conference, you have a unique opportunity to explore the renowned ARoS Art Museum, where art truly comes to life. We are excited to offer all attendees vouchers that can be used during your stay in Aarhus, giving you the chance to experience the museum’s extraordinary collections and exhibitions. Using Your Vouchers Your vouchers are valid from Saturday, November 30, 2024, through Sunday, December 8, 2024.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keynote Lauren Klein</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/lauren-klein/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/lauren-klein/</guid>
      <description>About Lauren We are happy to announce that Lauren Klein, Winship Distinguished Research Professor and Associate Professor in the departments of Quantitative Theory &amp; Methods and English at Emory University, will give a keynote speech at the Computational Humanities Research 2024 Conference. Lauren Klein also directs the Digital Humanities Lab at Emory University, and before moving to Emory, she taught in the School of Literature, Media, and Communication at Georgia Tech.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keynote Leon Derczynski</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/leon-derczynski/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/leon-derczynski/</guid>
      <description>About Leon We are happy to announce that Professor Leon Derczynski, principal research scientist in LLM Security at NVIDIA and prof in Natural Language Processing (NLP) at ITU Copenhagen (IT University of Copenhagen) will give a keynote speech at the Computational Humanities Research 2024 Conference in Aarhus, Denmark.&#xA;Professor Derczynski contributes to leading bodies on LLM securing, being on the OWASP LLM Top 10 core team, working on ML Commons, and founder of the ACL SIG on NLP Security.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Past Events</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/archive/</guid>
      <description>CHR2023 CHR2023 was a three-day conference held on December 6 to 8, 2023. The program committee and organizers accepted 49 papers, which have been published with CEUR-WS: https://ceur-ws.org/Vol-3558/. See https://2023.computational-humanities-research.org/ for more information about CHR2023.&#xA;CHR2022 CHR2022 was a three-day conference held on December 12 to 14, 2022. The program committee and organizers accepted 29 papers, which have been published with CEUR-WS: https://ceur-ws.org/Vol-3290/. See https://2022.computational-humanities-research.org/ for more information about CHR2022.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call for Bids to Host CHR2025</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/hosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/hosting/</guid>
      <description>The board of the Computational Humanities Society hereby invites proposals to host the annual CHR conference in December 2025. Some of the proposals will also be considered for CHR in 2026 and beyond. The number of (in-person) attendees to a CHR conference is likely to fall in the range of 150-250.&#xA;Deadline: November 10, 2024. We will announce the next conference’s location during CHR2024 in Aarhus in December 2024. Please send formal proposals or any questions by email to info@computational-humanities-research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/community/</guid>
      <description>We cordially invite you and other interested parties to join the Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/contact/</guid>
      <description>Community Please join our Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!&#xA;Contact For questions, ideas, or support, contact the organizers or drop us a line on the forum.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:11:58 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/cfp/</guid>
      <description>In the arts and humanities, the use of computational, statistical, and mathematical approaches has considerably increased in recent years. This research is characterized by the use of formal methods and the construction of explicit, computational models. This includes quantitative, statistical approaches, but also more generally computational methods for processing and analyzing data, as well as theoretical reflections on these approaches. Despite the undeniable growth of this research area, many scholars still struggle to find suitable research-oriented venues to present and publish computational work that does not lose sight of traditional modes of inquiry in the arts and humanities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper1/</guid>
      <description>Explainable Search and Discovery of Visual Cultural Heritage Collections with Multimodal Large Language Models (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Taylor Arnold and Lauren Tilton&#xA;Presented in Session 5B: Search &amp; Discovery&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Many cultural institutions have made large digitized visual collections available online, often under permissible re-use licences. Creating interfaces for exploring and searching these collections is difficult, particularly in the absence of granular metadata. In this paper, we introduce a method for using state-of-the-art multimodal large language models (LLMs) to enable an open-ended, explainable search and discovery interface for visual collections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper102/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper102/</guid>
      <description>Greatest Hits Versus Deep Cuts: Exploring Variety in Set-lists Across Artists and Musical Genres (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Edward Abel and Andrew Goddard&#xA;Presented in Session 8B: Popular Media&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Live music concert analysis provides an opportunity to explore cultural and historical trends. The art of set-list construction, of which songs to play, has many considerations for an artist, and the notion of how much variety different artists play is an interesting topic.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper104/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper104/</guid>
      <description>Textual Transmission without Borders: Multiple Multilingual Alignment and Stemmatology of the ``Lancelot en prose&#39;&#39; (Medieval French, Castilian, Italian) (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Matthias Gille Levenson, Lucence Ing and Jean-Baptiste Camps&#xA;Presented in Session 6B: Multilingualism &amp; Translation Studies&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This study focuses on the problem of multilingual medieval text alignment, which presents specific challenges, due to the absence of modern punctuation in the texts and the non-standard forms of medieval languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper106/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper106/</guid>
      <description>Patterns of Quality: Comparing Reader Reception Across Fanfiction and Commercially Published Literature (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Mia Jacobsen, Yuri Bizzoni, Pascale Feldkamp Moreira and Kristoffer L. Nielbo&#xA;Presented in Session 3A: Literary Canon &amp; Reception&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Recent work on the textual features linked to literary quality has primarily focused on commercially published literature, such as canonical or best-selling novels, that are systematically filtered by editorial and market mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper110/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper110/</guid>
      <description>Steps Towards Mining Manuscript Images for Untranscribed Texts: A Case Study From the Syriac Collection at the Vatican Library (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Luigi Bambaci, George Kiraz, Christine Roughan, Matthieu Freyder and Daniel Stökl Ben Ezra&#xA;Presented in Session 4B: Automatic Text Recognition&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Digital libraries and databases of texts are invaluable resources for researchers, yet their reliance on printed editions can lead to significant gaps and potentially exclude works without printed reproductions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper119/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper119/</guid>
      <description>On Classification with Large Language Models in Cultural Analytics (long paper)&#xA;Authors: David Bamman, Kent K. Chang and Li Lucy and Naitian Zhou&#xA;Presented in Session 4A: Large Language Models&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract In this work, we survey the way in which classification is used as a sensemaking practice in cultural analytics, and assess where large language models can fit into this landscape. We identify ten tasks supported by publicly available datasets on which we empirically assess the performance of LLMs compared to traditional supervised methods, and explore the ways in which LLMs can be employed for sensemaking goals beyond mere accuracy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper12/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper12/</guid>
      <description>Who Advertises in Newspapers? Data Criticism in Mining Historical Job Ads (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Klara Venglarova, Raven Adam, Wiltrud Mölzer, Saranya Balasubramanian, Jörn Kleinert, Manfred Füllsack and Georg Vogeler&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Digitized newspapers are a source of unique and rich historical data but pose significant challenges in the interpretation of results obtained through their mining. The JobAds project (FWF P35783) explores the evolution of the labor market through job advertisements from digitized newspapers between 1850-1950, aiming to reveal regional and temporal trends in job offers, required skills, media strategies, and social aspects such as gender-specific ads.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper121/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper121/</guid>
      <description>Promises from an Inferential Approach in Classical Latin Authorship Attribution (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Giulio Tani Raffaelli&#xA;Presented in Session 3B: Stylometry&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Applying stylometry to Authorship Attribution requires distilling the elements of an author&#39;s style sufficient to recognise their mark in anonymous documents. Often, this is accomplished by contrasting the frequency of selected features in the authors&#39; works. A recent approach, CP2D, uses innovation processes to infer the author&#39;s identity, accounting for their propensity to introduce new elements.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper122/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper122/</guid>
      <description>Does ChatGPT Have a Poetic Style? (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Melanie Walsh, Anna Preus and Elizabeth Gronski&#xA;Presented in Session 4A: Large Language Models&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Generating poetry has become a popular application of LLMs, perhaps especially of OpenAI&#39;s widely-used chatbot ChatGPT. What kind of poet is ChatGPT? Does ChatGPT have its own poetic style? Can it successfully produce poems in different styles? To answer these questions, we prompt the GPT-3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper123/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper123/</guid>
      <description>Deciphering Still Life Artworks with Linked Open Data (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Bruno Sartini&#xA;Presented in Session 1A: Visual Arts and Art History&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract The still life genre is a good example of how even the simplest elements depicted in an artwork can be carriers of deeper, symbolic meanings that influence the overall artistic interpretation of it. In this paper, we present an ongoing study on the use of linked open data (LOD) to quantitatively analyze the symbolic meanings of still life paintings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper124/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper124/</guid>
      <description>Once More, With Feeling: Measuring Emotion of Acting Performances in Contemporary American Film (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Naitian Zhou and David Bamman&#xA;Presented in Session 7B: Measuring Emotion &amp; Sentiment&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Narrative film is a composition of writing, cinematography, editing, and performance. While much computational work has focused on the writing or visual style in film, we conduct in this paper a computational exploration of acting performance. Applying speech emotion recognition models and a variationist sociolinguistic analytical framework to a corpus of popular, contemporary American film, we find narrative structure, diachronic shifts, and genre- and dialogue-based constraints located in spoken performances.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper128/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper128/</guid>
      <description>Automatic Translation Alignment Pipeline for Multilingual Digital Editions of Literary Works (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Maria Levchenko&#xA;Presented in Session 6B: Multilingualism &amp; Translation Studies&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This paper investigates the application of translation alignment algorithms in the creation of a Multilingual Digital Edition (MDE) of Alessandro Manzoni&#39;s Italian novel I promessi sposi (``The Betrothed&#39;&#39;), with translations in eight languages (English, Spanish, French, German, Dutch, Polish, Russian and Chinese) from the 19th and 20th centuries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper13/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper13/</guid>
      <description>Beyond the Register: Demographic Modeling of Arrest Patterns in 1879-1880 Brussels (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Folgert Karsdorp, Mike Kestemont and Margo de Koster&#xA;Presented in Session 7A: Social Patterns&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Unseen species models from ecology have recently been applied to censored historical cultural datasets to estimate unobserved populations. We extend this approach to historical criminology, analyzing the police registers of Brussels&#39; Amigo prison (1879-1880) using the Generalized Chao estimator.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper130/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper130/</guid>
      <description>Subversive Characters and Stereotyping Readers: Characterizing Queer Relationalities with Dialogue-Based Relation Extraction (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Kent K. Chang, Anna Ho and David Bamman&#xA;Presented in Session 1B: Classification &amp; Information Extraction&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Television is often seen as a site for subcultural identification and subversive fantasy, including in queer cultures. How might we measure subversion, or the degree to which the depiction of social relationship between a dyad (e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper132/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper132/</guid>
      <description>Treating Games as Plays? Computational Approaches to the Detection of Scenes in Game Dialogs (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Martin Schlenk, Thomas Efer and Manuel Burghardt&#xA;Presented in Session 8B: Popular Media&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Digital games are a complex multimodal phenomenon that is examined in a variety of ways by the highly interdisciplinary field of game studies. In this article, we focus on the structural aspect of the diegetic language of games and examine the extent to which established methods of computational drama analysis can also be successfully applied to digital games.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper133/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper133/</guid>
      <description>Modeling the Evolution of Harmony in Popular Music from Different Cultural Contexts (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Fabian C. Moss and Eita Nakamura&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Popular music often features a high amount of stable harmonic patterns, which facilitates the establishment of stylistic idioms and recognizability, and the changing frequencies of such patterns are closely linked to style and genre: new patterns arise while others die out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper135/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper135/</guid>
      <description>Early Modern Book Catalogues and Multilingualism: Identifying Multilingual Texts and Translations using Titles (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Yann Ryan and Margherita Fantoli&#xA;Presented in Session 6B: Multilingualism &amp; Translation Studies&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract With this paper we aim to assess whether Early Modern book titles can be exploited to track two aspects of multilingualism in book publishing: publications featuring multiple languages and the distinction between editions of works in their original language and in translation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper137/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper137/</guid>
      <description>On the Unity of Literary Change. The Development of Emotions in German Poetry, Prose, and Drama between 1850 and 1920 as a Test Case (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Leonard Konle, Merten Kröncke, Fotis Jannidis and Simone Winko&#xA;Presented in Session 8A: Cultural Dynamics&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract In this study, we use the development of emotions in German-language poetry, drama, and prose from 1850 to 1920 to informally test three hypotheses about literature: (1) Literature is a unified field, and therefore genres develop similarly at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper139/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper139/</guid>
      <description>Fine-Tuning Pre-Trained Language Models for Authorship Attribution of the Pseudo-Dionysian Ars Rhetorica (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Gleb Schmidt, Veronica Vybornaya and Ivan P. Yamshchikov&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This paper explores the use of pre-trained language models for Ancient Greek in the context of authorship attribution. The study adopts a two-step approach: first, the models are fine-tuned on a domain-specific corpus using a masked language modeling (MLM) objective; second, based on the fine-tuned model, a classifier is trained to address the authorship attribution task.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper140/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper140/</guid>
      <description>Sequencing Literary Reception: Trajectories of Russian Novels over the Afterlife Course (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Kim Alexander&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract The study explores literary recognition as a continuously generating new results process, as opposed to static models. Introducing sequence analysis to cultural analytics, it examines how literary trajectories of Russian pre-revolutionary novels unfold over time (1919-2022). After analyzing variations in publishing trajectories among school and non-school clusters, the paper explores the relationship between school and reprint domains.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper141/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper141/</guid>
      <description>Computational segmentation of Wayang Kulit video recordings using a Cross-Attention Temporal Model (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Hong Wei Shawn Liew and Miguel Escobar Varela&#xA;Presented in Session 1A: Visual Arts and Art History&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract We report preliminary findings on a novel approach to automatically segment Javanese wayang kulit (traditional leather puppet) performances using computational methods. We focus on identifying comic interludes, which have been the subject of scholarly debate regarding their increasing duration.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper15/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper15/</guid>
      <description>Abbreviation Application: A Stylochronometric Study of Abbreviations in the Oeuvre of Herne’s Speculum Scribe (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Caroline Vandyck and Mike Kestemont&#xA;Presented in Session 3B: Stylometry&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This research examines the Carthusian monastery of Herne, a major cultural hotspot during the Middle Ages. Between 1350 and 1400, the monks residing in Herne produced an impressive 46 production units, with 40 of them written in the Middle Dutch vernacular.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper17/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper17/</guid>
      <description>Integrating Visual and Textual Inputs for Searching Large-Scale Map Collections with CLIP (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Jamie Mahowald and Benjamin Charles Germain Lee&#xA;Presented in Session 5B: Search &amp; Discovery&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Despite the prevalence and historical importance of maps in digital collections, current methods of navigating and exploring map collections are largely restricted to catalog records and structured metadata. In this paper, we explore the potential for interactively searching large-scale map collections using natural language inputs (``maps with sea monsters&#39;&#39;), visual inputs (i.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper18/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper18/</guid>
      <description>A Methodology for Studying Linguistic and Cultural Change in China, 1900-1950 (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Spencer Dean Stewart&#xA;Presented in Session 5A: Linguistic Change&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This paper presents a quantitative approach to studying linguistic and cultural change in China during the first half of the twentieth century, a period that remains understudied in computational humanities research. The dramatic changes in Chinese language and culture during this time call for greater reflection on the tools and methods used for text analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper19/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper19/</guid>
      <description>Literary Time Travel: Distinguishing Past and Contemporary Worlds in Danish and Norwegian Fiction (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Jens Bjerring-Hansen, Ali Al-Laith, Daniel Hershcovich, Alexander Conroy and Sebastian Ørtoft Rasmussen&#xA;Presented in Session 2A: Literature&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract The classification of historical and contemporary novels is a nuanced task that has traditionally relied on expert literary analysis. This paper introduces a novel dataset comprising Danish and Norwegian novels from the last 30 years of the 19 th century, annotated by literary scholars to distinguish between historical and contemporary works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper20/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper20/</guid>
      <description>Viability of Zero-shot Classification and Search of Historical Photos (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Erika Maksimova, Mari-Anna Meimer, Mari Piirsalu and Priit Järv&#xA;Presented in Session 1A: Visual Arts and Art History&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Multimodal neural networks are models that learn concepts in multiple modalities. The models can perform tasks like zero-shot classification: associating images with textual labels without specific training. This promises both easier and more flexible use of digital photo archives, e.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper21/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper21/</guid>
      <description>The birth of French orthography. A computational analysis of French spelling systems in diachrony (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Simon Gabay and Thibault Clérice&#xA;Presented in Session 5A: Linguistic Change&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract The 17th~c. is crucial for the French language, as it sees the creation of a strict orthographic norm that largely persists to this day. Despite its significance, the history of spelling systems remains however an overlooked area in French linguistics for two reasons.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper23/</guid>
      <description>Catching Feelings: Aspect-Based Sentiment Analysis for Fanfiction Comments about Greek Myth (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Julia Neugarten, Tess Dejaeghere, Pranaydeep Singh, Amanda Robin Hemmons and Julie M. Birkholz&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract The application of sentiment analysis in literary studies has been limited and often criticized, yet aspect-based sentiment analysis (ABSA) offers interesting applications in this domain because it addresses some limitations of traditional SA tools and provides a more detailed and context-sensitive analysis of sentiment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper24/</guid>
      <description>Rediscovering the 1890s: A Norwegian Poetry Corpus (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Ranveig Kvinnsland, Ingerid Løyning Dale and Lars Magne Tungland&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract What language was used most for written poetry in the 1890s in Norway? What was the gender distribution of published poets in that decade? To what degree does the lyrical subject &#34;reveal&#34; itself, explicitly or implicitly, in the poems? This article presents answers to these questions in relation to corpus of poetry written by Norwegian and Danish poets, published between 1890 and 1899.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper27/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper27/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the Evolution of Gender Power Difference through the Omegaverse Trope on AO3 Fanfiction (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Xiaoyan Yang and Federico Pianzola&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This study examines the evolution of gender power differences within the Omegaverse trope on the Archive of Our Own (AO3) fanfiction platform. The Omegaverse, a fan created trope defined by distinct secondary gender categories (Alpha, Beta, Omega), provides a lens to explore and critique gender dynamics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper28/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper28/</guid>
      <description>Automated Image Color Mapping for a Historic Photographic Collection (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Taylor Arnold and Lauren Tilton&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract In the 1970s, the United States Environmental Protection Agency sponsored Documerica, a large-scale photography initiative to document environmental subjects nation-wide. While over 15,000 digitized public-domain photographs from the collection are available online, most of the images were scanned from damaged copies of the original prints.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper29/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper29/</guid>
      <description>Getting to grippe with influenza: an investigation of why the disease is called that (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Maria Bekker-Nielsen Dunbar, Manex Agirrezabal and Tønnes Bekker-Nielsen&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract We investigate influenza-related terminology to gain a deeper understanding of what may have driven the choice in disease name when competing options were available. It is unclear why influenza in English should be called ``influenza&#39;&#39; and not ``grippe&#39;&#39; as the latter is seemingly the most common term for influenza within Indo-European languages.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper30/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper30/</guid>
      <description>Does Context Matter ? Enhancing Handwritten Text Recognition with Metadata in Historical Manuscripts (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Benjamin Kiessling and Thibault Clérice&#xA;Presented in Session 4B: Automatic Text Recognition&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract The digitization of historical manuscripts has significantly advanced in recent decades, yet many documents remain as images without machine-readable text. Handwritten Text Recognition (HTR) has emerged as a crucial tool for converting these images into text, facilitating large-scale analysis of historical collections.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper32/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper32/</guid>
      <description>Treebanks for the ordinary working grammarian (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Joel Priestley, Anders Nøklestad, Kristin Hagen, Anu Laanemets and Dag Trygve Truslew Haug&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract In this paper we present how three treebanks of Norwegian have been incorporated in the Glossa search interface, allowing users without specialized training to formulate queries based on syntactic information. One of the treebanks contains written material (mostly newspaper text, but also blogs, magazines and other genres) and the two other treebanks are based on transcriptions of spoken dialects.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper35/</guid>
      <description>Enhancing Arabic Maghribi Handwritten Text Recognition with RASAM 2: A Comprehensive Dataset and Benchmarking (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Chahan Vidal-Gorène, Clément Salah, Noëmie Lucas, Aliénor Decours-Perez and Antoine Perrier&#xA;Presented in Session 4B: Automatic Text Recognition&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Recent advancements in handwritten text recognition (HTR) for historical documents have demonstrated high performance on cursive Arabic scripts, achieving accuracy comparable to Latin scripts. The initial RASAM dataset, focused on three Arabic Maghribi manuscripts, facilitated rapid coverage of new documents via fine-tuning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper36/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper36/</guid>
      <description>Global Coherence, Local Uncertainty - Towards a Theoretical Framework for Assessing Literary Quality (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Yuri Bizzoni, Pascale Feldkamp and Kristoffer Nielbo&#xA;Presented in Session 2A: Literature&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract A theoretical framework for evaluating literary quality through analyzing narrative structures using simplified narrative representations in the form of story arcs is presented. This framework proposes two complementary models: the first employs Approximate Entropy to measure local unpredictability, while the second utilizes fractal analysis to assess global coherence.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper38/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper38/</guid>
      <description>Censorship as a Dissociative Force: A Case of Sovremennik Magazine, 1847–1866 (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Ekaterina Vozhik, Kirill Maslinsky and Roman Lisiukov&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract The article focuses on the systemic effects of censorship that manifest themselves in the content of published materials that successfully passed the censorship filters. We understand censorship as a special kind of collective imagination about the (in)acceptable, inherent in a particular political context and influencing the decision-making logic by different actors.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper39/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper39/</guid>
      <description>Epistemic Capture through Specialization in Post-World War II Parliamentary Debate (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Ruben Ros and Melvin Wevers&#xA;Presented in Session 7A: Social Patterns&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This study examines specialization in Dutch Lower House debates between 1945 and 1994. We study how specialization translates in the phenomenon of ``epistemic capture&#39;&#39; in democratic politics. We combine topic modeling, network analysis and community detection to complement lexical ``distant reading&#39;&#39; approaches the history of political ideas with a network-based analysis that illuminates political-intellectual processes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper4/</guid>
      <description>FAIR Turn in Epigraphy: Low Barrier Pathways to Quantitative and Reproducible Research in Latin Epigraphy (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Petra Heřmánková, Brian Ballsun-Stanton and Ray Laurence&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract The application of FAIR (Findable, Accessible, Interoperable, Reusable) principles can revolutionise the epigraphic discipline by facilitating quantitative and reproducible research. Despite the richness of Latin inscriptions, the lack of low-barrier tools for accessing and analysing these datasets has hindered large-scale studies and the uptake of FAIR and Open Science principles in ancient studies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper41/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper41/</guid>
      <description>A quantitative study of gender representation and authors&#39; gender in a large-market print medium (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Christoph Bartl, Sharwin Rezagholi and Mareike Schumacher&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract We analyse gender representation in articles published by the Austrian daily newspaper &#39;Der Standard&#39; in the years 2021 and 2022. We use named entity recognition and automated gender classification of first names to count the number of female and male persons in articles.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper42/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper42/</guid>
      <description>Computational Paleography of Medieval Hebrew Scripts (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Berat Kurar-Barakat, Daria Vasyutinsky-Shapira, Sharva Gogawale and Mohammad Suliman and Nachum Dershowitz&#xA;Presented in Session 6B: Multilingualism &amp; Translation Studies&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract We present ongoing work as part of an international multidisciplinary project, called MiDRASH, on the computational analysis of medieval manuscripts. We focus here on clustering manuscripts written in Ashkenazi square script using a dataset of 206 pages from 59 manuscripts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper43/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper43/</guid>
      <description>Clustering Tasks and Decision Trees with Augustan Love Poets: Cohesion and Separation in Feature Importance Extraction (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Carlos Javier Nusch, Gimena Del Río Riande, Leticia Cagnina, Marcelo Luis Errecalde and Leandro Antonelli&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This article extends various automatic text analysis tasks from previous works by applying natural language processing techniques to a corpus of Latin texts from the 1st century BC and 1st century AD.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper46/</guid>
      <description>Models of Literary Evaluation and Web 2.0. An Annotation Experiment with Goodreads Reviews (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Simone Rebora and Gabriele Vezzani&#xA;Presented in Session 6A: Annotation&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract In the context of the Web 2.0, user-genrated reviews are becoming more and more prominent. The particular case of book reviews, often shared through digital social reading platforms such as Goodreads or Wattpad, is of particular interest, in that it offers scholars data regarding literary reception of unprecedented size and diversity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper49/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper49/</guid>
      <description>Context is Key(NMF): Modelling Topical Information Dynamics in Chinese Diaspora Media (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Ross Deans Kristensen-McLachlan, Rebecca M.M. Hicke, Márton Kardos and Mette Thunø&#xA;Presented in Session 8A: Cultural Dynamics&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Does the People&#39;s Republic of China (PRC) interfere with European elections through ethnic Chinese diaspora media? This question forms the basis of an ongoing research project exploring how PRC narratives about European elections are represented in Chinese diaspora media, and thus the objectives of PRC news media manipulation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper5/</guid>
      <description>Sub-optimal Recall in Visual Cluster Retrieval: When Clusters Look Like Bridges (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Mathieu Jacomy, Matilde Ficozzi and Anders K. Munk&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Force-directed node placement algorithms, a popular technique to visualise networks, are known to optimize ``cluster separability&#39;&#39;: when sets of densely connected nodes get represented as well-separated groups of dots. Using these techniques leads us to conceive networks as sets of clusters connected by bridges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper52/</guid>
      <description>Extracting Social Connections from Finnish Karelian Refugee Interviews Using LLMs (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Joonatan Laato, Jenna Kanerva, John Loehr, Virpi Lummaa and Filip Ginter&#xA;Presented in Session 1B: Classification &amp; Information Extraction&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract We performed a zero-shot information extraction study on a historical collection of 89,339 brief Finnish-language interviews of refugee families relocated post-WWII from Finnish Eastern Karelia. Our research objective is two-fold. First, we aim to extract social organizations and hobbies from the free text of the interviews, separately for each family member.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper55/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper55/</guid>
      <description>Visual Navigation of Digital Libraries: Retrieval and Classification of Images in the National Library of Norway’s Digitised Book Collection (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Marie Roald, Magnus Breder Birkenes and Lars Gunnarsønn Bagøien Johnsen&#xA;Presented in Session 5B: Search &amp; Discovery&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Digital tools for text analysis have long been essential for the searchability and accessibility of digitised library collections. Recent computer vision advances have introduced similar capabilities for visual materials, with deep learning-based embeddings showing promise for analysing visual heritage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper56/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper56/</guid>
      <description>The discourse of the French method: making old knowledge on market gardening accessible to machines and humans. (short paper)&#xA;Authors: David Colliaux and Remi van Trijp&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract A vast amount of our cultural heritage is at risk of getting lost because it resides in old books that are difficult to access. It is therefore important to make this information available to human readers but also to machine analysis, so that new representations and insights based on this knowledge can be constructed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper57/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper57/</guid>
      <description>Admiration and Frustration: A Multidimensional Analysis of Fanfiction (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Mia Jacobsen and Ross Deans Kristensen-McLachlan&#xA;Presented in Session 8B: Popular Media&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Why do people write fanfiction? How, if at all, does fanfiction differ from the source material on which it is based? In this paper, we use quantitative text analysis to address these questions by investigating linguistic differences and similarities between fan-produced texts and their original sources.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper58/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper58/</guid>
      <description>Bringing Rome to Life: Evaluating Historical Image Generation (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Phillip B. Ströbel, Zejie Guo, Ülkü Karagöz, Eva Maria Willi and Felix K. Maier&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This study evaluates the potential of AI image generation for visualising historical events, focusing on two ancient Roman scenarios: the Roman triumph and the Lupercalia festival. Using DALL-E 3, we generated 600 images based on 100 prompts derived from scientific texts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper59/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper59/</guid>
      <description>Recognising non-named spatial entities in literary texts: a novel spatial entities classifier (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Daniel Kababgi, Giulia Grisot, Federico Pennino and Berenike Herrmann&#xA;Presented in Session 2A: Literature&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Predicting spatial representations in literature is a challenging task that requires advanced machine learning methods and manual annotations. In this paper, we present a study that leverages manual annotations and a BERT language model to automatically detect and recognise non-named spatial entities in a historical corpus of Swiss novels.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper6/</guid>
      <description>Quantitative Framework for Word-Color Association and Application to 20th Century Anglo-American Poetry (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Sungpil Wang and Juyong Park&#xA;Presented in Session 2B: Semantic Analysis&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Color symbolism is considered a critical element in art and literature, yet determining the relationship between colors and words has remained largely subjective. This research presents a systematic methodology for quantifying the correlation between language and color. We utilize text-based image search, optical character recognition (OCR), and advanced image processing techniques to establish a connection between words and their corresponding color distributions in the CIELch color space.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper60/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper60/</guid>
      <description>SCIENCE IS EXPLORATION: Computational Frontiers for Conceptual Metaphor Theory (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Rebecca M. M. Hicke and Ross Deans Kristensen-McLachlan&#xA;Presented in Session 5A: Linguistic Change&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Metaphors are everywhere. They appear extensively across all domains of natural language, from the most sophisticated poetry to seemingly dry academic prose. A significant body of research in the cognitive science of language argues for the existence of conceptual metaphors, the systematic structuring of one domain of experience in the language of another.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper61/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper61/</guid>
      <description>Bootstrap Distance Imposters: High precision authorship verification with improved interpretability (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Ben Nagy&#xA;Presented in Session 3B: Stylometry&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This paper describes an update to the open-source Python implementation of the General Imposters method of authorship verification by Mike Kestemont et al. The new algorithm, called Bootstrap Distance Imposters (henceforth BDI), incorporates a key improvement introduced by Potha and Stamatatos, as well as introducing a novel method of bootstrapping that has several attractive properties when compared to the reference algorithm.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper62/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper62/</guid>
      <description>Addressing Uncertainty according to the Annotator&#39;s Expertise in Archaeological Data Collections: an Approach from Fuzzy Logic (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Patricia Martin-Rodilla and Leticia Tobalina-Pulido&#xA;Presented in Session 6A: Annotation&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Archaeological data allow us to synthetically represent the past of individuals and communities over time. This complex representation task requires an amalgamation of variables and makes the intrinsic data vagueness. The study of vagueness as an archaeological data dimension has become a dynamic focus of archaeologists&#39; work in recent years, presenting theoretical and practical approaches for the representation, mainly with fuzzy logic, of archaeological variables.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper63/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper63/</guid>
      <description>Across the Pages: A Comparative Study of Reader Response to Web Novels in Chinese and English on Qidian and WebNovel (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Ze Yu and Federico Pianzola&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract The evolution of online reading platforms has transformed engagement with fiction, with platforms like WebNovel bridging cultural boundaries through translated Chinese web novels. This study employs topic modeling to compare reader responses to the same stories published in Chinese on Qidian and in English on WebNovel, focusing on English and Chinese language comments.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper67/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper67/</guid>
      <description>In the Context of Narrative, we Never Properly Defined the Concept of Valence (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Peter Boot, Angel Daza, Carsten Schnober and Willem van Hage&#xA;Presented in Session 7B: Measuring Emotion &amp; Sentiment&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Valence is a concept that is increasingly being used in the computational study of narrative texts. We discuss the history of the concept and show that the word has been interpreted in various ways.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper70/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper70/</guid>
      <description>Locating the Leading Edge of Cultural Change (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Sarah Griebel, Becca Cohen, Lucian Li, Jiayu Liu, Jaihyun Park, Jana Perkins and Ted Underwood&#xA;Presented in Session 8A: Cultural Dynamics&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Measures of textual similarity and divergence are increasingly used to study cultural change. But which measures align, in practice, with social evidence about change? We apply three different representations of text (topic models, document embeddings, and word-level perplexity) to three different corpora (literary studies, economics, and fiction).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper71/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper71/</guid>
      <description>Transformation of Composition and Gaze Interaction in Noli Me Tangere Depictions from 1300–1600 (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Pepe Ballesteros Zapata, Nina Arnold, Vappu Lukander, Ludovica Schaerf and Dario Negueruela del Castillo&#xA;Presented in Session 1A: Visual Arts and Art History&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This paper examines the development of figure composition and gaze dynamics between Mary Magdalene and Christ in Italian noli me tangere depictions from 1300 to 1600 in the context of the emergence of perspective painting.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper73/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper73/</guid>
      <description>Page Embeddings: Extracting and Classifying Historical Documents with Generic Vector Representations (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Carsten Schnober, Renate Smit, Manjusha Kuruppath, Kay Pepping, Leon van Wissen and Lodewijk Petram&#xA;Presented in Session 1B: Classification &amp; Information Extraction&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract We propose a neural network architecture designed to generate region and page embeddings for boundary detection and classification of documents within a large and heterogeneous historical archive. Our approach is versatile and can be applied to other tasks and datasets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper74/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper74/</guid>
      <description>Direct and Indirect Annotation with Generative AI: A Case Study into Finding Animals and Plants in Historical Text (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Arjan van Dalfsen, Folgert Karsdorp, Ayoub Bagheri, Dieuwertje Mentink, Thirza van Engelen and Els Stronks&#xA;Presented in Session 6A: Annotation&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This study explores the use of generative AI (GenAI) for annotation in the humanities, comparing direct and indirect annotation approaches with human annotations. Direct annotation involves using GenAI to annotate the entire corpus, while indirect annotation uses GenAI to create training data for a specialized model.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper75/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper75/</guid>
      <description>Combining Automatic Annotation with Human Validation for the Semantic Enrichment of Cultural Heritage Metadata (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Eirini Kaldeli, Alexandros Chortaras, Vassilis Lyberatos, Jason Liartis, Spyridon Kantarelis and Giorgos Stamou&#xA;Presented in Session 6A: Annotation&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract The addition of controlled terms from linked open datasets and vocabularies to metadata can increase the discoverability and accessibility of digital collections. However, the task of semantic enrichment requires a lot of effort and resources that cultural heritage organizations often lack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper76/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper76/</guid>
      <description>Literary Canonicity and Algorithmic Fairness: The Effect of Author Gender on Classification Models (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Ida Marie S. Lassen, Pascale Feldkamp Moreira and Yuri Bizzoni and Kristoffer Nielbo&#xA;Presented in Session 3A: Literary Canon &amp; Reception&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This study examines gender biases in machine learning models that predict literary canonicity. Using algorithmic fairness metrics like equality of opportunity, equalised odds, and calibration within groups, we show that models violate the fairness metrics, especially by misclassifying non-canonical books by men as canonical.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper78/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper78/</guid>
      <description>Discoverability in a Digital Library: A Study of “Rabbit Holes” within Gallica’s corpus (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Anne-Laure Tettoni and Simon Dumas Primbault&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract The phenomenon of aimless web navigation, often compared to falling &#34;down the rabbit hole,&#34; brings to light significant aspects of the Internet&#39;s &#34;long tail&#34; concept. This research examines whether longer, non-goal-oriented web sessions genuinely lead users into the long tail of digital libraries, thereby exploring the discoverability of cultural heritage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper79/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper79/</guid>
      <description>Exploration of Event Extraction Techniques in Late Medieval and Early Modern Administrative Records (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Ismail Prada Ziegler&#xA;Presented in Session 1B: Classification &amp; Information Extraction&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract While an increasing amount of studies exploring named entity recognition in historical corpora are published, application of other information extraction tasks such as event extraction remains scarce. This study explores two accessible methods to facilitate the detection of events and the classification of entities into roles: rule-based systems and RNN-based machine learning techniques.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper80/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper80/</guid>
      <description>The GOLEM-Knowledge Graph and Search Interface: Perspectives into Narrative and Fiction (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Franziska Pannach, Luotong Cheng and Federico Pianzola&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This contribution presents the GOLEM Knowledge Graph and interface, offering different perspectives into content-related data and metadata from the domain of fanfiction narratives. The Knowledge Graph is aligned with common ontologies and vocabularies from the domains of narrative and cultural heritage.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper82/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper82/</guid>
      <description>Assessing Burial Mound Intervisibility and Prominence at Regional Scale (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Adela Sobotkova&#xA;Presented in Session 1A: Visual Arts and Art History&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Visibility and intervisibility have been important aspects of spatial analysis in landscape archaeological studies, but remain hampered by computational intensity, small-scale study area, edge effects, and bare-earth digital elevation models. This paper assesses intervisibility and prominence in a dataset of over 1000 burial mounds in the Middle Tundzha River watershed in Bulgaria.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper86/</guid>
      <description>Univariate Statistical Analysis of a Non-Canonical Literary Genre. Quantifying German-Language One-Act Plays (1740–1850) (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Viktor J. Illmer, Dîlan Canan Çakir, Frank Fischer, Lilly Welz and Carsten Milling&#xA;Presented in Session 3A: Literary Canon &amp; Reception&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This article explores the use of metadata to analyse German-language one-act plays from 1740 to 1850, addressing the need to expand beyond canonical texts in literary studies. Utilising the Database of German-Language One-Act Plays, we examine aspects such as the number of scenes and characters as well as the role of different original languages on which the translated plays in the corpus are based.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper9/</guid>
      <description>Multilingual Stylometry: The influence of language on the performance of authorship attribution using corpora from the European Literary Text Collection (ELTeC) (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Christof Schöch, Julia Dudar, Evgeniia Fileva and Artjoms Šeļa&#xA;Presented in Session 3B: Stylometry&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Stylometric authorship attribution is concerned with the task of assigning texts of unknown, pseudonymous or disputed authorship to their most likely author, often based on a comparison of the frequency of a selected set of features that represent the texts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper90/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper90/</guid>
      <description>Animacy in German Folktales (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Julian Häußler, Janis von Keitz and Evelyn Gius&#xA;Presented in Session 2A: Literature&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This paper explores the phenomenon of animacy in prose by the example of German folktales. We present a manually annotated corpus of 19 German folktales from the Brothers Grimm collection and train a classifier on these annotations. Building on previous work in animacy detection, we evaluate the classifier’s performance and its application to a larger corpus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper92/</guid>
      <description>Domain Adaptation with Linked Encyclopedic Data: A Case Study for Historical German (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Thora Hagen&#xA;Presented in Session 2B: Semantic Analysis&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This paper outlines a proposal for the use of knowledge graphs for historical German domain adaptation. From the EncycNet project, the encyclopedia-based knowledge graph from the early 20th century was borrowed to examine whether text-based domain adaptation using the source encyclopedia&#39;s text or graph-based adaptation produces a better domain-specific model.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper93/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper93/</guid>
      <description>And then I saw it: Testing Hypotheses on Turning Points in a Corpus of UFO Sighting Reports (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Jan Langenhorst, Robert C. Schuppe and Yannick Frommherz&#xA;Presented in Session 7A: Social Patterns&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract As part of developing a Computational Narrative Understanding, modeling events within stories has recently received significant attention within the digital humanities community. Most of the current research aims at good performance when predicting events.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper94/</guid>
      <description>Revolution + Love: Measuring the Entanglements of State Violence and Emotions in Early PRC (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Maciej Kurzynski and Aaron Gilkison&#xA;Presented in Session 7A: Social Patterns&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This paper examines the relationship between violent discourse and emotional intensity in the early revolutionary rhetoric of the People&#39;s Republic of China (PRC). Using two fine-tuned bert-base-chinese models—one for detecting violent content in texts and another for assessing their affective charge—we analyze over 185,000 articles published between 1956 and 1989 in the People&#39;s Liberation Army Daily ( Jiefangjun Bao ), the official journal of China&#39;s armed forces.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper95/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper95/</guid>
      <description>Tracing the Development of the Virtual Particle Concept Using Semantic Change Detection (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Michael Zichert and Adrian Wüthrich&#xA;Presented in Session 2B: Semantic Analysis&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Virtual particles are peculiar objects. They figure prominently in much of theoretical and experimental research in elementary particle physics. But exactly what they are is far from obvious. In particular, to what extent they should be considered real remains a matter of controversy in philosophy of science.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper96/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper96/</guid>
      <description>Remember to Forget: A Study on Verbatim Memorization of Literature in Large Language Models (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Xinhao Zhang, Olga Seminck and Pascal Amsili&#xA;Presented in Session 4A: Large Language Models&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract We examine the extent to which English and French literature is memorized by freely accessible LLMs, using a name cloze inference task (which focuses on the model&#39;s ability to recall proper names from a book).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper97/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper97/</guid>
      <description>Latent Structures of Intertextuality in French Fiction (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Jean Barré&#xA;Presented in Session 2A: Literature&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract Intertextuality is a key concept in literary theory that challenges traditional notions of text, signification or authorship. It views texts as part of a vast intertextual network that is constantly evolving and being reconfigured. This paper argues that the field of computational literary studies is the ideal place to conduct a study of intertextuality since we have now the ability to systematically compare texts with each others.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper98/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper98/</guid>
      <description>Sentiment Below the Surface: Omissive and Evocative Strategies in Literature and Beyond (long paper)&#xA;Authors: Pascale Feldkamp, Ea Overgaard Lindhardt, Kristoffer L. Nielbo and Yuri Bizzoni&#xA;Presented in Session 7B: Measuring Emotion &amp; Sentiment&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract As they represent one of the most complex forms of expression, literary texts continue to challenge Sentiment Analysis (SA) tools, often developed for other domains. At the same time, SA is becoming an increasingly central method in literary analysis itself, which raises the question of what are the challenges inherent to literary SA.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper99/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/paper99/</guid>
      <description>Text Mining to unveil Prehistoric Pastness in Museums (short paper)&#xA;Authors: Haley Anne Schwartz, Paula Jardón Giner and Xavier Rubio Campillo&#xA;Presented in Poster Session&#xA;Paper: Download PDF&#xA;Abstract This paper is a presentation of a current work in progress, specifically the exploratory phase for determining a methodological framework, clear objectives, and establishing preliminary results to guide the future direction of the project. The paper sees the application of text analysis to a corpus body of texts with a focus on highlighting heritage and intersectional data present within these texts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/about/</guid>
      <description> The Computational Humanities Research (CHR) community is an international and interdisciplinary community that supports researchers with an interest in computational approaches to the humanities. Learn more about the people behind CHR2024 and the organisation of CHR:&#xA;People → Journal → Community → Archive → </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accepted Papers</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/papers/</guid>
      <description>Viability of Zero-shot Classification and Search of Historical Photos(long)Erika Maksimova, Mari-Anna Meimer, Mari Piirsalu and Priit Järv&#xA;Transformation of Composition and Gaze Interaction in Noli Me Tangere Depictions from 1300–1600(short)Pepe Ballesteros Zapata, Nina Arnold, Vappu Lukander, Ludovica Schaerf and Dario Negueruela del Castillo&#xA;Deciphering Still Life Artworks with Linked Open Data(short)Bruno Sartini&#xA;Computational segmentation of Wayang Kulit video recordings using a Cross-Attention Temporal Model(short)Hong Wei Shawn Liew and Miguel Escobar Varela</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accomodation in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/accomodation-in-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/accomodation-in-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Aarhus offers a range of excellent hotels – from well-known international ones to unique accommodations. Get an overview of the hotels here.&#xA;We recommend that participants book their stay at one of the hotels listed below. Networking with fellow researchers is a key aspect of any conference, and this year&amp;rsquo;s event is designed to foster meaningful connections. By providing a range of accommodation options and encouraging attendees to stay at the same hotels, we hope to create more opportunities for interaction outside of formal sessions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHR Journal</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/journal/</guid>
      <description>The Cambridge University Press journal Computational Humanities Research (CHR) is the official journal of the CHR Conference. CHR is an open access journal in the computational humanities, publishing transdisciplinary papers that are grounded in humanities research questions and use computational, quantitative methodologies to analyse humanities data in its various forms.&#xA;CHR publishes research that tackles big questions and solves problems pertaining to the humanities through advanced computational methods, contributing empirically to major theoretical, cultural, and historical inquiry.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHR2024 Best Paper Awards</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/best-paper-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/best-paper-awards/</guid>
      <description>CHR2024 showcased outstanding work, highlighting cutting-edge computational approaches to humanities research. A heartfelt thank you to everyone who participated, whether by presenting your work or contributing to meaningful discussions at the conference.&#xA;We are delighted to reveal the winners of the Best Long Paper and Best Short Paper Awards. With so many exceptional submissions, we are pleased to also give honourable mentions to the two runners-up in each category.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CHR2024 Programme</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/programme/</guid>
      <description>Programme for the pre-conference workshops on Tuesday, 3rd December 2024, and the main conference days on Wednesday, Thursday, and Friday, 4th-6th December 2024. See all accepted papers.&#xA;The main venue address of CHR2024 is Bartholins Allé 8, 8000 Aarhus C. See Finding the Venue.&#xA;Note: Changes may occur in the programme. Please check regularly for the latest information.&#xA;Tuesday Wednesday Thursday Friday Tuesday, December 3, 2024 (Pre-conference workshops) 09:00 - 12:30 Workshop sessions Workshop A: Building 1325, Room 028 Workshop B: Heimdal Conference Center 12:30 - 13:30 Lunch 13:30 - 17:00 Workshop sessions Workshop A: Building 1325, Room 028 Workshop B: Heimdal Conference Center Parallel Workshops Workshop A: Digital Methods for Mythological Research dm4myth aims to bring together researchers from various disciplines who are interested in studying myths with digital tools and methods.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conference Dinner at Restaurant Havnær</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/conference-dinner/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/conference-dinner/</guid>
      <description>Image credit: Restaurant Havnær Join us for the conference dinner on December 5th at Restaurant Havnær, a name that translates to &amp;ldquo;close to the ocean&amp;rdquo; in Danish. Nestled at the edge of Aarhus Ø, this beautiful venue offers breathtaking views over Aarhus Bay, creating the perfect setting for a memorable evening.&#xA;At Havnær, the focus is on authentic experiences, combining exquisite gastronomy with warm, informal hospitality. Their approach reflects the charm of Jutland, meeting guests at eye level and offering a relaxed atmosphere where you can simply sit back, enjoy the moment, and take in the stunning surroundings from the SHIP building.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Culinary Delights in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/culinary-delights-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/culinary-delights-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Aarhus boasts a vibrant and diverse dining scene, offering something for every palate. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a gourmet aficionado or simply in search of a satisfying meal, the city has plenty to explore. For a casual start, head to the Latin Quarter or Jægergårdsgade, where you&amp;rsquo;ll find a wide range of dining options.&#xA;Fine Dining For those seeking fine dining, Aarhus is home to several Michelin-starred restaurants, which you can explore.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diversity and Inclusion at CHR2024</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/diversity-and-inclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/announcements/diversity-and-inclusion/</guid>
      <description>New initiatives, like the Anti-Discrimination Committee and reduced fees, reinforce the CHR2024 Conference’s commitment to accessibility and inclusivity, ensuring all participants feel valued and supported. Since its inception five years ago, the Computational Humanities Research (CHR) Conference has developed into a prominent and well-regarded event, attracting researchers who apply computational methods across various humanities fields. This growth has enriched the CHR community, diversifying both the range of topics explored and the contributors involved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding the Conference Venue</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/finding-the-venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/finding-the-venue/</guid>
      <description>The main address of the CHR2024 conference is Bartholins Allé 8, 8000 Aarhus C, where the registration and breakfast take place on the first day. For other details on transportation, see also Getting Around in Aarhus and Conference Dinner Transport.&#xA;Map of the Venue At CHR2024, all locations are conveniently set within a short walking distance. See the overview below:&#xA;A Building 1321 Registration and Breakfast on Wednesday (December 4, 2024)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting around in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/getting-around-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/getting-around-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Discover the many travel options that Aarhus has, and read more about how to buy tickets for public transport in Aarhus.&#xA;For a venue map, visit Finding the Venue. Details on CHR&amp;rsquo;s guided transport to the conference dinner are available at Conference Dinner Transport.&#xA;Travel Options Walking The entire city is clean, compact and well-organised, which makes walking an excellent and enjoyable way to get around. To walk from the centre of the city to the university takes approximately 40 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>People</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/people/</guid>
      <description>Programme Chairs Wouter Haverals, Princeton University Marijn Koolen, Huygens Institute, DHLab - KNAW Humanities Cluster Laure Thompson, Princeton University Local Organizers Kristoffer Nielbo, Center for Humanities Computing, Aarhus University Line E. Sørensen, Center for Humanities Computing, Aarhus University Ross Deans Kristensen-McLachlan, Center for Humanities Computing, Aarhus University Mina Almasi, Center for Humanities Computing, Aarhus University Programme Committee Tara Andrews, University of Vienna Maria Antoniak, University of Colorado Boulder Taylor Arnold, University of Richmond Rebekah Baglini, Aarhus University David Bamman, University of California, Berkeley Jean Barré, ENS-PSL Andreas Baumann, University of Vienna Nicolas Baumard, CNRS Kaspar Beelen, School of Advanced Study, University of London Yuri Bizzoni, Aarhus University Katherine Bode, Australian National University Emanuela Boros, EPFL Ryan Brate, University of Amsterdam Judith Brottrager, TU Darmstadt Tom Brughmans, Aarhus University Annelen Brunner, Institut für deutsche Sprache Manuel Burghardt, Computational Humanities, University of Leipzig Patrick Burns, University of Texas at Austin Florian Cafiero, Sciences Po Paris Jean-Baptiste Camps, École nationales des chartes Javier Cha, The University of Hong Kong Kent Chang, University of California, Berkeley Thibault Clérice, ALMANaCH, Inria Mariona Coll Ardanuy, PRHLT Research Center, Universitat Politècnica de València Charles de Dampierre, ENS Paris Simon DeDeo, Carnegie Mellon University Quinn Dombrowski, Stanford University Antoine Doucet, University of La Rochelle Marten During, Luxembourg Centre for Contemporary and Digital History (C2DH) Anton Ehrmanntraut, University of Würzburg Marieke van Erp, KNAW Humanities Cluster Pascale Feldkamp, CHCAA Elena Fernandez Fernandez, University of Zurich Mark Finlayson, Florida International University Heather Froehlich, University of Arizona Evelyn Gius, Technical University of Darmstadt Cesar Gonzalez-Perez, Incipit CSIC Thora Hagen, Universität Würzburg Serge Heiden, ENS de Lyon Simon Hengchen, iguanodon.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sightseeing in Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/sights-in-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/sights-in-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>Experience Aarhus before and after the CHR2024 Conference&#xA;Aarhus, Denmark’s second-largest city and affectionately known as “The City of Smiles,” offers a delightful mix of modern attractions and historic charm. Whether you arrive early or extend your stay after the conference, there’s plenty to discover. To help you plan, we have curated some recommendations for must-see experiences in and around Aarhus.&#xA;Activities ARoS Art Museum As a participant in the upcoming CHR2024 conference, you have a unique opportunity to explore the renowned ARoS Art Museum, where art truly comes to life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travelling to Aarhus</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/travelling-to-aarhus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/travelling-to-aarhus/</guid>
      <description>There is a wide range of travel options for you to arrive to Aarhus - just as you would like:&#xA;By Air Travelling to/from:&#xA;Aarhus Airport Aarhus Airport (Tirstrup) is located 40 km north of the city and offers direct international flights to a number of European destinations, for instance Oslo, Stockholm, Gothenburg, Manchester, London (Stansted and Gatwick), Berlin, Munich, Nice, Rome and Cyprus. Please visit their website for information on flight arrival/departure times.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Venue</title>
      <link>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://2024.computational-humanities-research/venue/</guid>
      <description>The CHR2024 Conference will be held on December 4-6 with workshops taking place on the December 3rd. The conference will take place in Aarhus, Denmark at Aarhus University, in their historical buildings located in the city center, close to the vibrant urban environment as well as nature, including parks, forest and the coastline.&#xA;The main address of the CHR2024 conference is Bartholins Allé 8, 8000 Aarhus C, where the registration and breakfast take place on the first day.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
